Contact

ebukoye@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/emanb (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Communication

Python (Programming Language)

Certifications

Certificate in Information Security Management Principles (CISMP)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Honors-Awards

UKMT Senior Mathematical Challenge Bronze Certificate Tallis Habits Award - Discipline Level 2 Award in Sports Leadership (QCF)

Emmanuel Bukoye

Final Year Computer Science Student at University of Bath | Outreach Ambassador | Online Tutor London

Summary

My interest in Computing got started when I researched and learnt about the various encryption and sandboxing methods that are used in the iPhone. When the first iPhone was released, I was particularly intrigued by why iOS is rarely infected by viruses and malicious software in comparison to other mobile operating systems. Learning that one of the many factors for this is Apple's thorough checks for malware and encryption of their apps, I developed an interest in cryptography. Reading Tony Crilly's "50 Maths Ideas You Really Need To Know", I realised that prime numbers are the foundation of cryptography algorithms such as RSA, which depends on the fact that prime factorisation of numbers uses a significant amount of time and processing power. Since this is supported by the absence of an efficient algorithm for prime factorisation, this gave me an insight into the mathematics behind Computer Science, illustrating the importance of problem-solving skills in this field. This eventually lead me to study this subject at the University of Bath.

Experience

MyTutor.co.uk
Online Tutor
September 2018 - Present (3 years 2 months)

- Teaches students Mathematics from 11+ to A-Level and Further Mathematics from 11+ to GCSE Level
- Teaches GCSE Maths on a weekly basis via MyTutor's Schools Programme

University of Bath 3 years 1 month

Outreach Ambassador June 2021 - Present (5 months)

Student Ambassador November 2018 - Present (3 years)

Bath, United Kingdom

- Leading campus tours and interacting with prospective students at open day events
- Answering questions about the university, the city of Bath and my experiences from prospective students and/or their parents
- Leading individual conversations with prospective students concerning my course
- Participating in calling campaigns which involve calling offer-holders of my course to answer any queries they have concerning the university, the city of Bath, and the course

Peer Mentor

April 2019 - March 2020 (1 year)

- Helps incoming first-year Computer Science students settle into university well
- Provides support to my group of students regarding the subject

Student Fundraiser

November 2019 - December 2019 (2 months)

This role involves contacting our alumni to raise funds for the university's Alumni Fund. In total we reached over 1000 alumni, raising over £100,000 going towards the University's Alumni Fund, helping provide Gold Scholarships for disadvantaged students, funding for cutting edge research, and placement grants to financially support students.

Academic Rep for BSc Computer Science October 2018 - September 2019 (1 year)

Bath, United Kingdom

- Evaluated units for the current course in line with the principles of UoB's Curriculum Transformation project
- Surveyed students and alumni on the experience of Computer Science at Bath, what skills & competencies they developed on the course, and which skills & competencies they think are relevant in their industry
- Took in the opinions and thoughts of students concerning the course and raised it to the director of studies

PwC

Cyber Security Associate
July 2020 - July 2021 (1 year 1 month)

In this role, I am currently working within PwC's Ethical Hacking team, which is allowing me to develop my understanding of enterprise networking, computer security, and the operation and tooling used within a real-world penetration testing team. This role is also helping me further develop my expertise with Windows and Linux technologies, and completing software development tasks with Infrastructure as Code technologies such as Ansible, Google Cloud Platform and Terraform.

techUK

Intern

February 2017 - February 2017 (1 month)

London, United Kingdom

During my week placement, I worked with techUK's membership engagement team and carried out a project for them to research the people and organisations that are their members, to find what they want and need from techUK. This was a good opportunity to find out more about the tech industry, and the roles in it. At the end of the week, I performed a presentation to an audience, including the CEO of Sthree, explaining my experiences during the week.

CORPORATE WORSHIP AND TRAINING LIMITED

Teacher & Web Developer (Volunteer) September 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 2 months)

London, United Kingdom

Helped design and build a new website for CWTL. While working there, I maintained the website and updated it where necessary along with adding new sections. In addition, I helped teach their students to play the drums via drum learning software.

Education

University of Bath

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018 - 2022)

Thomas Tallis 6th Form

A Level, Mathematics, Further Mathematics & Physics · (2016 - 2018)

Thomas Tallis School

GCSE · (2011 - 2016)